<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:3000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-05-05T19:29:24+04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:3000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Seven Times Bitcoin</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/24/seven-times-bitcoin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seven Times Bitcoin" /><published>2022-04-24T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2022-04-24T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/24/seven-times-bitcoin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/24/seven-times-bitcoin.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="seven-times-bitcoin-miners-made-the-world-a-better-place">Seven times Bitcoin miners made the world a better place</h1>
<h4 id="btc-mining-and-the-miners-themselves-seem-to-be-doing-more-than-just-securing-the-bitcoin-network">BTC mining and the miners, themselves, seem to be doing more than just securing the Bitcoin network.</h4>

<p><img src="../../../../assets/images/posts/img52.jpeg" alt="'image'" /></p>

<p>What do a swimming pool, beef jerky, a caravan, timber, animal waste, a Guatemalan lake and a high school have in common? </p>

<p>They’ve all been saved by Bitcoin (<a href="https://cointelegraph.com/bitcoin-price">BTC</a>) mining. From reusing “waste” heat to getting the job done — to receiving a cool blast of air to dehydrate meat, to cleaning up pollutants, Bitcoin mining does more than just secure the network. </p>

<p>Here’s a round-up of seven times Bitcoin mining lent a hand or simply made the world a better place.</p>

<h3 id="free-bitcoin-mining-education-in-washington">Free Bitcoin mining education in Washington</h3>

<p><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/bitmain-signs-500mw-joint-venture-with-sustainable-btc-miner-merkle-standard">Sustainable Bitcoin mining company Merkle Standard</a> has taken Bitcoin mining education into its own hands. In partnership with Bitmain, they recently gifted the latest in Bitcoin mining technology to Newport High School, a high school in Washington state. </p>

<p>Plus, they donated $10,000 and are promoting education about Bitcoin in the hope that it will, “plant a seed that encourages lifelong interest in blockchain and digital mining.”</p>

<p>Along with the check, Ruslan Zinurov, Merkle Standard’s CEO, told Cointelegraph that they will also invite students to their “data center to check on their machine that is hashing to their school’s wallet.” Zinurov told Cointelegraph:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“It is our top priority to get the community excited about Bitcoin and we can’t think of a better way to do this than to educate the local students.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Adam Delderfield, business development manager at Bitmain — <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/crypto-mining-s-cost-how-has-hardware-availability-changed-the-industry">the holding company for the Antminer Bitcoin miners</a> — told Cointelegraph, “Digital currency mining proceeds from this gift will go directly to education,” adding that “Bitcoin mining and proof-of-work represent an exciting new industry that opens up numerous new opportunities.”</p>

<p><img src="https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2022-04/f01ae23d-cd3e-402a-922a-643840af0b19.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><em>Adam Delderfield from Bitmain in the suit, and Monty Stahl from Merkle Standard with the students. Source: Bitmain</em></p>

<h3 id="bitcoin-miner-beef-jerky-cooked-up-by-the-business-cat-chef">Bitcoin miner beef jerky cooked up by the Business Cat chef</h3>

<p>Bitcoiner Business Cat, who wishes to remain nameless, uses the heat vented by Bitcoin mining to dry out meat to be made into beef jerky. They told Cointelegraph, “Bitcoin miners have one hell of an excess of supply of dry, heated air,” so it makes sense to funnel that heat over strips of beef to make jerky. </p>

<p>Similar to Merkle Standard, for the Business Cat, the jerky cooking process is not about making money: “My normal food dehydrator uses much less energy than an S9, but hashpower dried jerky just tastes better.”</p>

<p>They told Cointelegraph that “the support of the plebs on Bitcoin Twitter” persuaded them to try out the idea. They joked that “most of us Bitcoin plebs are natural loners, so a few words of praise or support from others on the path goes a long way.”</p>

<p>The Bitcoin community is increasingly supportive of ideas that promote Bitcoin philosophy and Bitcoin-only ideas, <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/building-businesses-in-the-spirit-of-bitcoin-the-bitcoin-hostel">from a Bitcoin hostel in Portugal</a> to a <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/why-is-a-guatemalan-mayor-mining-bitcoin-tackling-fud-with-biogas-and-btc">Bitcoin lake project in Guatemala.</a></p>

<p><img src="https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2022-04/fb9dcd60-86f2-41ca-ad4b-1c0214a68af5.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><em>The modified Bitcoin miner that cleans the air while funneling it for use on food. Source: Twitter</em></p>

<p>Business Cat is delighted with their experience and suggests others take up home mining. They combined life advice with Bitcoin mining advice explaining to Cointelegraph:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Should you mine Bitcoin at home? Yes. Should you learn to be a better chef? Also yes.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="bitcoin-heats-my-swimming-pool">Bitcoin heats my swimming pool</h3>

<p>Bitcoin enthusiast Jonathan Yuan found a cheaper, faster and more stable way of heating his swimming pool in Minnesota, all thanks to Bitcoin mining.</p>

<p>Thanks to immersion heating, <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/water-great-idea-bitcoin-mining-heats-this-swimming-pool">Bitcoin now powers up his pool</a>. Even though Yuan doesn’t care for swimming, his kids are happy to swim in the pool while he secures the Bitcoin network.</p>

<p><img src="https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2022-04/a1233b80-acd0-4064-a47b-0b9a4a7ffa49.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><em>Yuan’s Bitcoin miner heated pool. Source: Twitter</em> </p>

<p>Yuan told Cointelegraph that the whole experiment went so swimmingly that he’s now planning on heating “the whole house.” </p>

<h3 id="propane-gas-tank-heater-broke-down-bitcoin-miner-to-the-rescue">Propane gas tank heater broke down? Bitcoin miner to the rescue!</h3>

<p>Michael Schmid is a well-traveled, savvy Bitcoiner. When his caravan’s propane gas heater broke down, he refitted the vehicle to be warmed by the “<a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/gas-heater-broke-down-i-ll-just-heat-my-caravan-with-a-bitcoin-miner">waste” heat from an S9 Bitcoin miner</a>.</p>

<p>Schmid told Cointelegraph that he saves “around 50% of the propane costs, which is around $2.7 per day.”</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Now the fun part, the miner produces around 0.00006259 BTC per day (with the current difficulty and 13 TH/s) on the current price of 38 thousand. This is $2.40 per day, so we technically heat the airstream for free.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p><img src="https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2022-04/8c49a919-5229-450c-8db2-6c8aa2655cd3.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><em>Schmid’s airstream kept warm with a Bitcoin miner, in a box just behind the wheel. Source: Schmid</em></p>

<p>Plus<strong>,</strong> a kick in the teeth to the anti-Bitcoin environmentalists — heating the Schmid family airstream with Bitcoin rather than propane gas is better for the planet.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Our Airstream has solar panels on top of it that can generate up to 400W of energy, so technically of the 1400W that the miner uses, 400W of them are self-generated and fully renewable.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="bitcoin-miner-waste-heat-dries-out-timber">Bitcoin miner waste heat dries out timber </h3>

<p>Kryptovault is a Norwegian Bitcoin mining company with arguably the <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/green-oasis-for-bitcoin-mining-norway-has-almost-1-of-global-btc-hash-rate">greenest credentials among any industry</a>. Powered by 100% hydropower, the energy it uses solves valid blocks on the Bitcoin blockchain and the heat generated by the miners blows over damp logs from a local timber mill.</p>

<p><img src="https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2022-04/cb8cb4d1-9890-4efd-b347-8702efc22594.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><em>Timber waiting to be dried by Bitcoin miner’s waste heat at Kryptovault’s mining facility. Source: Kryptovault</em></p>

<p>In a video made by the company, Sveni Bjerke, CEO of local firewood company Varma, which receives the miner-dried logs, says that they are “only using excess heat from the data center.”</p>

<p>The environmental success of the project has spurred further partnerships. Kjetil Hove Pettersen, CEO of KryptoVault, told Cointelegraph that drying out seaweed for local companies is coming soon, and they are “constantly looking for new ways of utilizing our waste heat.”</p>

<p>Pettersen explained, “Approximately 99% of our electric energy turns into thermal energy.” </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“ As we know, energy is never truly lost, it only changes form. So this is a way of us to utilize this energy twice and support other local industries in the process. I can’t think of any better industrial use-cases than what we are doing.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="promoting-financial-and-energy-autonomy-in-guatemala">Promoting financial and energy autonomy in Guatemala </h3>

<p>In south Guatemala, a team of Bitcoin miners <a href="http://v/">donated an S9 to the local mayor</a> and the mining proceeds are being used to repair a wastewater treatment plant. </p>

<p><img src="https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2022-04/3277eab4-d3a2-4a2f-a96b-0f869a56fffd.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><em>Bill Whittaker and Patrick Melder, on the right, installing the Bitcoin miner. Source: Twitter</em></p>

<p>Bitcoin mining in the economically disadvantaged region has boosted incomes while improving the air quality. </p>

<p>Plus, as Bill Whittaker, a co-founder of Bitcoin Lake, told Cointelegrpah, the team is “self-funding carbon-negative Bitcoin mining R&amp;D.” Two high school students, Madaket and Kate, are planning a trip down to “LakeBitcoin in early May to deliver the S17s they have been working on.”</p>

<p>The Bitcoin miners they bring will join the first Bitcoin miner, and naturally will be powered by renewable energy — in this case, biogas. Biogas is growing in <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/the-bitcoin-shitcoin-machine-mining-btc-with-biogas">popularity as an energy source</a> for Bitcoin mining.</p>

<p><img src="https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2022-04/1209bbe1-199b-4808-8b74-4c7e7115bc77.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><em>Madaket and Kate posing with their Bitmain miner under a solar panel. Source: Whittaker</em></p>

<h3 id="bitcoin-mining-grows-flowers-and-food">Bitcoin mining grows flowers and food</h3>

<p>A greenhouse in the Netherlands is heated by Bitcoin miners rather than natural gas. That’s according to Bert de Groot, founder of Bitcoin Bloem.</p>

<p><img src="https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2022-04/c9d99d7e-83a3-4d48-b536-7f420ae6058c.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><em>The Bitcoin miner camouflaged among hydrangeas. Source: Twitter</em></p>

<p>In partnership with a large greenhouse, they “placed a Bitcoin miner to reduce the use of natural gas, the prices of which have skyrocketed, and heat the greenhouse with miner heat instead.” De Groot continued: </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“The family that owns the greenhouse first put electric heaters because of the 6x cost of natural gas, they now get paid for their electricity, which is used for mining, and receive the heat for free.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It’s a win-win situation. After all, who can say no to flowers? </p>

<p><img src="https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2022-04/5559ef98-dfc9-460b-8fda-9fae5cb341ba.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><em>One of the Bitcoin flowers. Source: Twitter</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Seven times Bitcoin miners made the world a better place BTC mining and the miners, themselves, seem to be doing more than just securing the Bitcoin network.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Genesis Digital Assets</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/23/genesis-digital-assets.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Genesis Digital Assets" /><published>2022-04-23T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/23/genesis-digital-assets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/23/genesis-digital-assets.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="genesis-digital-assets-plans-100-clean-energy-mining-center-in-sweden">Genesis Digital Assets Plans 100% Clean Energy Mining Center in Sweden</h1>
<h3 id="the-new-facility-will-be-powered-by-a-mix-of-hydro-nuclear-and-wind-energy-sources">The new facility will be powered by a mix of hydro, nuclear and wind energy sources.</h3>

<p><a href="https://www.coindesk.com/author/aoyon-ashraf/"><strong>By Aoyon Ashraf</strong></a></p>

<p><img src="../../../../../assets/images/posts/img13.jpeg" alt="'image'" /></p>

<p>Genesis Digital Assets, a privately held industrial-scale bitcoin miner, plans to start a new self-hosted bitcoin mining data center in Sweden, which is expected to have up to 100 megawatts of power capacity.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>The energy mix at the facility in Sweden will be 54.5% hydro, 42.8% nuclear and 2.7% wind powered, a company spokesperson told CoinDesk.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>“This latest expansion aligns with GDA’s focus to identify ways to power our facilities with clean energy while also creating jobs for the local economy,” said Tim Liepold, head of power at Genesis Digital Assets.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>In September, Genesis <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/business/2021/09/21/genesis-digital-assets-raises-431m-for-expansion/">raised 431 million</a> to expand its bitcoin mining operations in North America and the Nordic region in a funding round that was led by Paradigm Ventures. That was on top of the $125 million the miner <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2021/07/28/genesis-digital-assets-raises-125m-to-fuel-us-and-nordic-expansion/">raised</a> in July in a funding round that was led by Kingsway Capital.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>In November, Genesis said that it is building a new self-hosted bitcoin mining data center in West Texas with <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/business/2021/11/01/genesis-digital-expands-in-us-with-300mw-bitcoin-mining-facility-in-texas/">300 megawatt of capacity</a>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Genesis Digital Assets is different from Genesis, the crypto lending firm owned by CoinDesk parent company Digital Currency Group.</p>
  </li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Genesis Digital Assets Plans 100% Clean Energy Mining Center in Sweden The new facility will be powered by a mix of hydro, nuclear and wind energy sources.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Environmental Groupswsj</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/22/environmental-groupsWSJ.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Environmental Groupswsj" /><published>2022-04-22T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2022-04-22T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/22/environmental-groupsWSJ</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/22/environmental-groupsWSJ.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="environmental-groups-pressure-bitcoin-community-to-lower-energy-use">Environmental Groups Pressure Bitcoin Community to Lower Energy Use</h1>
<h4 id="consortium-launches-effort-advocating-changes-to-the-cryptocurrencys-code">Consortium launches effort advocating changes to the cryptocurrency’s code</h4>

<p><img src="../../../../assets/images/posts/img14.jpeg" alt="'image'" /></p>

<p>A consortium of environmental groups launched a campaign on Monday seeking to change b
itcoin’s code to decrease its energy use, which has grown substantially in the past few years.</p>

<p>Bitcoin is popular among some investors, but its energy use has <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/bitcoin-miners-are-giving-new-life-to-old-fossil-fuel-power-plants-11621594803?mod=article_inline">riled environmental groups</a>, alarmed some lawmakers, and put the cryptocurrency at odds with a green movement that has some supporters on Wall Street. The new campaign aims to persuade people involved with the cryptocurrency, from mining companies to investors to software developers, that a change is better for the environment and bitcoin’s reputation and support.</p>

<p>Greenpeace USA, Environmental Working Group and others will run ads in media outlets such as the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/market-data/quotes/NYT">New York Times</a>, Politico and The Wall Street Journal highlighting bitcoin’s environmental impact and advocating for change. The campaign is funded by Ripple co-founder Chris Larsen, who isn’t representing the cryptocurrency firm in this endeavor. Mr. Larsen said he provided $5 million. </p>

<p>Some of the ads are aimed at prominent bitcoin backers, such as <a href="https://www.wsj.com/market-data/quotes/TSLA">Tesla Inc</a>. Chief Executive <a href="https://www.wsj.com/topics/person/elon-musk">Elon Musk</a>, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/market-data/quotes/SQ">Block Inc</a>. founder Jack Dorsey and Fidelity Investments Chief Executive Abby Johnson.</p>

<p>There have been attempts to lower bitcoin’s energy footprint. A consortium of about 250 companies, including miners such as Hut 8 Mining Corp., support <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/crypto-miners-struggle-to-cut-carbon-emissions-11634808781?mod=article_inline">the Crypto Climate Accord</a>, which aims to switch the industry over to renewable energy sources. Some miners, like Easton, Md.-based <a href="https://www.wsj.com/market-data/quotes/WULF">TeraWulf Inc</a>. , are working to create a zero-emissions operation.</p>

<p>The new campaign isn’t anti-bitcoin, said Michael Brune, the former executive director of the Sierra Club who is advising the campaign. Rather, he said, it argues that climate change has reached a critical point, and bitcoin, the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/biden-to-order-study-of-cryptocurrency-risk-creation-of-u-s-digital-currency-11646823600?mod=article_inline">most valuable cryptocurrency</a> in terms of market capitalization, is contributing too much to global warming.</p>

<p>“It’s important for anyone in a position to act, to act,” he said. “You can’t ignore that we are in a climate emergency.”</p>

<h4 id="share-your-thoughts">SHARE YOUR THOUGHTS</h4>

<p><em>How might bitcoin mining be done in a more environmentally sustainable way? Join the conversation below.</em></p>

<p>The goal is to persuade bitcoin’s community of investors and backers to change the network’s code, removing the “proof of work” mechanism that requires bitcoin “miners” to expend a certain amount of energy while processing transactions to earn rewards in newly created bitcoin. The change could drastically reduce bitcoin’s energy use, Mr. Brune said.</p>

<p>Bitcoin’s energy usage is a defense mechanism designed to protect the network. Because it is an open-source project, anybody can run the bitcoin software. But the network requires miners to expend vast amounts of computing power to make it prohibitively expensive for somebody to take over the network, which could allow them to create counterfeit bitcoins or erase transactions.</p>

<p>The Cambridge Centre for Alternative Finance estimates that the bitcoin network uses slightly more energy a year, 134.9 terawatt hours, than Norway, at 124.3 terawatt hours. The research institute said, however, that bitcoin uses less energy than is lost in the U.S. during electricity transmission. </p>

<p>Bitcoin Miners Tap Hydropower as Environmental Criticism Grows</p>

<p><img src="https://m.wsj.net/video/20211014/cryptocarbon101421/cryptocarbon101421_960x540.jpg" alt="Bitcoin Miners Tap Hydropower as Environmental Criticism Grows" /></p>

<p>Bitcoin Miners Tap Hydropower as Environmental Criticism GrowsPlay video: Bitcoin Miners Tap Hydropower as Environmental Criticism Grows</p>

<p>A bitcoin mining facility in upstate New York is using electricity from a local hydroelectric plant powered by the Niagara River. The company is part of a group of miners attempting to make the industry more sustainable, both environmentally and financially. Illustration: Alex Kuzoian/WSJ</p>

<p>Some bitcoin miners have addressed the issue by using more renewable energy sources to power their computers, but Messrs. Brune and Larsen think that isn’t enough.</p>

<p>Bitcoin’s environmental effects have been an issue for years, but the people in control of it have rejected the kinds of changes being proposed. Moreover, because bitcoin isn’t owned by a company, changing the code requires nearly all of the parties involved in its maintenance—something on the order of 90% or more—to agree on a change.</p>

<p>The Ethereum network also uses proof of work, but is changing to a model called proof of stake, which essentially swaps energy for cryptocurrency. That change, the implementation of which has been delayed several times for technical reasons, is expected to reduce Ethereum’s electricity usage by 99%. The campaign is hoping to effect a similar switch for bitcoin.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Environmental Groups Pressure Bitcoin Community to Lower Energy Use Consortium launches effort advocating changes to the cryptocurrency’s code]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Scientific</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/20/scientific.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Scientific" /><published>2022-04-20T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2022-04-20T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/20/scientific</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/20/scientific.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="core-scientific-announces-preliminary-2021-financial-results-2022-operating-guidance-and-february-updates">Core Scientific Announces Preliminary 2021 Financial Results, 2022 Operating Guidance and February Updates</h1>

<ul>
  <li>Preliminary 2021 revenue of $515 million to $545 million, net income of $50 million to $60 million and adjusted EBITDA of $225 million to $235 million</li>
  <li>Expects total operating hashrate of 31 EH/s to 40-42 EH/s, and operating capacity from 1.0 GW to 1.2-1.3 GW in 2022</li>
  <li>Produced 981 bitcoins, increased self-mining hashrate to 8.2 EH/s and increased hosted hashrate to 7.7 EH/s in February 2022</li>
</ul>

<p>AUSTIN, Texas–(<a href="https://www.businesswire.com/">BUSINESS WIRE</a>)–<strong><a href="https://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.corescientific.com%2F&amp;esheet=52590455&amp;newsitemid=20220307005380&amp;lan=en-US&amp;anchor=Core+Scientific%2C+Inc.&amp;index=1&amp;md5=cc60708445567e8c2d53278f78ee1292">Core Scientific, Inc.</a></strong> (NASDAQ: CORZ) (“Core Scientific” or “the Company”), a leader in high-performance, net carbon neutral blockchain infrastructure and software solutions, today announced preliminary financial results for the fiscal year ending December 31, 2021, initial fiscal year 2022 operating guidance and February production and operations updates.</p>

<p><strong>2021 PRELIMINARY RESULTS AND EARNINGS RELEASE DATE</strong></p>

<p>“Our team’s outstanding efforts this past year delivered strong financial results that comfortably exceeded our expectations,” said Mike Levitt, Core Scientific Chief Executive Officer. “We expect 2021 revenue to be $515 million to $545 million, net income of $50 million to $60 million and adjusted EBITDA of $225 million to $235 million. We ended the year having produced 5,769 bitcoins and operating total hashrate of 13.5 EH/s, well ahead of our anticipated 11.0 EH/s. We are pleased with the performance of our company, our team and our infrastructure, and look forward to continuing to build value for our shareholders in 2022.”</p>

<p>Core Scientific expects to release fourth quarter and full fiscal year 2021 results after the market closes on March 29, 2022 and will hold a conference call later that day. Please visit the Events and Presentations section of the Company’s website to learn more:</p>

<p><a href="https://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Finvestors.corescientific.com%2Finvestors%2Fevents-and-presentations%2Fdefault.aspx&amp;esheet=52590455&amp;newsitemid=20220307005380&amp;lan=en-US&amp;anchor=https%3A%2F%2Finvestors.corescientific.com%2Finvestors%2Fevents-and-presentations%2Fdefault.aspx&amp;index=2&amp;md5=55a1c00779539c45480454b6d62f4bd1">https://investors.corescientific.com/investors/events-and-presentations/default.aspx</a></p>

<p><strong>2022 OPERATING GUIDANCE</strong></p>

<p>“We believe that we are well positioned to achieve 40 to 42 EH/s of total hashrate by year end 2022, distributed approximately evenly between our self-mining and hosting segments. Demand for our hosting capacity remains strong and continues to exceed our available supply. Our construction and power team is on pace to achieve 1.2 to 1.3 GW of operating infrastructure by year end to continue expanding our hosting and self-mining capacity,” Mr. Levitt added.</p>

<p><em>Summary of preliminary 2021 financial results and 2022 operating guidance:</em></p>

<table><tbody><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><b>Preliminary Financial Results</b></p></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><b>Full Year 2021</b></p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Total Revenue</p></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>$515 to $545 million</p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Net Income</p></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>$50 to $60 million</p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Adjusted EBITDA</p></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>$225 to $235 million</p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Total Hashrate (EH/s)</p></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>13.5 EH/s</p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Operating Megawatts ("MW")</p></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>457 MW</p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1">&nbsp;</td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><b>Operating Guidance</b></p></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><b>Full Year 2022</b></p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Total Hashrate (EH/s)</p></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>40 to 42 EH/s</p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Operating Gigawatts ("GW")</p></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"></td><td colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>1.2 to 1.3 GW</p></td></tr></tbody></table>

<p><strong>CAPITAL MARKETS ACTIVITIES</strong></p>

<p>Core Scientific’s Board of Directors voted unanimously to accelerate by approximately four months the expiration of the “lock-up” restricting the sale of stock held by early (pre-public) investors in the company. The Board determined that it was in the best interests of the company to increase the shares available for trading in the open market.</p>

<p>“By enabling early private round investors to sell shares we hope to increase our traded float,” commented Mr. Levitt. “We welcome these sales as we believe that increasing our float will benefit our company and is in the best long-term interests of all of our shareholders. Affiliates of the company, including myself, my fellow board members Matt Minnis and Darin Feinstein, and executive officers Todd DuChene, Michael Trzupek and Brian Neville, are not currently eligible to sell shares under the exemption provided by Rule 144.”</p>

<p><strong>FEBRUARY UPDATE</strong></p>

<p>Mr. Levitt continued, “We ended 2021 operating data centers in four states with total mining capacity of 13.5 EH/s. Two months later we were operating in five states, with a sixth state in view, and had increased our hashrate to 15.9 EH/s. Across our business, our team is delivering strong growth and outstanding results that continue to position Core Scientific as a leading blockchain infrastructure provider and digital asset self-miner.”</p>

<p><em>Self-Mining</em></p>

<p>Core Scientific’s self-mining operations produced 981 bitcoins in February, averaging 35 bitcoins per day, an increase from January’s 34.7 daily average, and representing a year over year increase of 313%. As of February 28, 2022, the Company held 7,355 bitcoins produced from operations.</p>

<p>As of February month end, Core Scientific operated its own fleet of more than 80,000 bitcoin miners, producing 8.2 EH/s.</p>

<p><em>Hosting</em></p>

<p>In addition to its self-mining fleet, as of February 28, 2022, Core Scientific provided infrastructure, technology and operating support for a diverse group of customers representing 7.7 EH/s.</p>

<p>“Strong demand for hosting is driven by both additional capacity requests from existing customers and inquiries from new customers,” said Mr. Levitt. “While requests for hosting currently exceed our available supply, planned infrastructure additions in late 2022 should create capacity for additional hosting customers.”</p>

<p><em>Infrastructure</em></p>

<p>Phase 1 of the Company’s Denton, Texas facility began operation on February 22 with an initial operating capacity approaching 22 MW. When completed, the Company anticipates the entire site will comprise seven of the Company’s proprietary cathedral structures as well as a fleet of three-dozen Antbox mining containers. The Company expects to approach full operating capacity of 300 MW at the Denton data center by the end of 2022.</p>

<p><em>Grid Support</em></p>

<p>In the month of February, the Company powered-down portions of its operations in two states on 14 separate occasions. Aggregate electrical curtailment for these events exceeded 4,400 megawatt-hours. As the Company has demonstrated throughout the winter months, it will continue to work with the communities and utility companies in which it operates to enable and ensure electrical grid stability.</p>

<p><strong>ABOUT CORE SCIENTIFIC</strong></p>

<p>Core Scientific is one of the largest publicly traded, net carbon-neutral blockchain infrastructure providers and miners of digital assets in North America. Core Scientific has operated blockchain infrastructure in North America since 2017, using its facilities and intellectual property portfolio that has grown to more than 70 patents or applications for digital asset hosted mining and self-mining. Core Scientific operates data centers in Georgia, Kentucky, North Carolina, North Dakota and Texas, and expects to commence operations in Oklahoma in the second half of 2022. Core Scientific’s proprietary Minder® fleet management software combines the Company’s hosting expertise with data analytics to deliver maximum uptime, alerting, monitoring and management of all miners in the Company’s network. To learn more, visit <a href="https://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.corescientific.com&amp;esheet=52590455&amp;newsitemid=20220307005380&amp;lan=en-US&amp;anchor=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.corescientific.com&amp;index=3&amp;md5=3992bd6fe11dd2766c803acdcd0ee618">http://www.corescientific.com</a>.</p>

<p>As of September 30, 2021, over 50% of the power used in Core Scientific’s operation was generated from non-carbon emitting sources by local power providers pursuant to long-term power contracts. The Company determines whether power is generated from non-emitting energy sources from dispatch reports or grid generation mix reports provided by the Company’s power providers. Based on these reports Core Scientific purchased Green-e certified renewable energy credits (“RECs”) to offset 100% of the carbon produced as a result of its contracted power. The Company expects to maintain its net carbon neutrality by increasing its overall use of renewable power and by purchasing RECs when necessary.</p>

<p><strong>FORWARD LOOKING STATEMENTS AND EXPLANATORY NOTES</strong></p>

<p>This press release includes “forward-looking statements’’ within the meaning of the “safe harbor” provisions of the United States Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. Forward-looking statements may be identified by the use of words such as “estimate,” “plan,” “project,” “forecast,” “intend,” “will,” “expect,” “anticipate,” “believe,” “seek,” “target” or other similar expressions that predict or indicate future events or trends or that are not statements of historical matters. These forward-looking statements include, but are not limited to, those related to the Company’s ability to scale and grow its business, source clean and renewable energy, the advantages and expected growth of the Company, future estimates of revenue, net income and adjusted EBITDA, future estimates of computing capacity and operating capacity, future demand for hosting capacity, future estimate of hashrate (including mix of self-mining and hosting) operating gigawatts, future projects in construction or negotiation and future expectations of operation location, orders for miners and critical infrastructure, future estimates of self-mining capacity, the public float of the Company’s shares, future Infrastructure additions and their operational capacity, and operating capacity and site features of the Company’s operations center in Denton, Texas. These statements are provided for illustrative purposes only and are based on various assumptions, whether or not identified in this press release, and on the current expectations of the Company’s management. These forward-looking statements are not intended to serve, and must not be relied on by any investor, as a guarantee, an assurance, a prediction or a definitive statement of fact or probability. Actual events and circumstances are difficult or impossible to predict and will differ from assumptions. Many actual events and circumstances are beyond the control of the Company. These forward-looking statements are subject to a number of risks and uncertainties, including those identified in the Company’s reports filed with the U.S. Securities &amp; Exchange Commission, and if any of these risks materialize or our assumptions prove incorrect, actual results could differ materially from the results implied by these forward-looking statements. Accordingly, undue reliance should not be placed upon the forward-looking statements.</p>

<p>Year over year comparisons are based on the combined results of Core Scientific and its acquired entities.</p>

<p>Core Scientific provides this and any future similar unaudited updates to provide shareholders with visibility into the Company’s results and progress toward previously announced capacity and operational projections.</p>

<p><strong>ADJUSTED EBITDA</strong></p>

<p>Adjusted EBITDA is a non-GAAP financial measure defined as our net income or (loss), adjusted to eliminate the effect of (i) interest income, interest expense, and other income (expense), net; (ii) provision for income taxes; (iii) depreciation and amortization; (iv) stock-based compensation expense; and (v) certain additional non-cash and non-recurring items. For additional information, including the reconciliation of net income (loss) to Adjusted EBITDA, please refer to the table below. We believe Adjusted EBITDA is an important measure because it allows management, investors, and our board of directors to evaluate and compare our operating results, including our return on capital and operating efficiencies, from period-to-period by making the adjustments described above. In addition, it provides useful information to investors and others in understanding and evaluating our results of operations, as well as provides a useful measure for period-to-period comparisons of our business, as it removes the effect of net interest income (expense), taxes, certain non-cash items, variable charges, and timing differences. Moreover, we have included Adjusted EBITDA in this press release because it is a key measurement used by our management internally to make operating decisions, including those related to operating expenses, evaluate performance, and perform strategic and financial planning.</p>

<p>The above items are excluded from our Adjusted EBITDA measure because these items are non-cash in nature, or because the amount and timing of these items is unpredictable, not driven by core results of operations and render comparisons with prior periods and competitors less meaningful. However, you should be aware that when evaluating Adjusted EBITDA, we may incur future expenses similar to those excluded when calculating these measures. Our presentation of this measure should not be construed as an inference that its future results will be unaffected by unusual or non-recurring items. Further, this non-GAAP financial measure should not be considered in isolation from, or as a substitute for, financial information prepared in accordance with GAAP. We compensate for these limitations by relying primarily on GAAP results and using Adjusted EBITDA on a supplemental basis. Our computation of Adjusted EBITDA may not be comparable to other similarly titled measures computed by other companies because not all companies calculate this measure in the same fashion. You should review the reconciliation of net income (loss) to Adjusted EBITDA below and not rely on any single financial measure to evaluate our business.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Core Scientific Announces Preliminary 2021 Financial Results, 2022 Operating Guidance and February Updates]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Navajo</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/19/navajo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Navajo" /><published>2022-04-19T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2022-04-19T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/19/navajo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/19/navajo.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="why-the-navajo-are-mining-bitcoin">Why The Navajo Are Mining Bitcoin</h1>
<p>William Foxley - <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/publishers/bitcoin-magazine">Bitcoin Magazine</a></p>

<p><img src="../../../../assets/images/posts/img11.jpeg" alt="'image'" /></p>

<p>The technology of bitcoin provides an avenue for growth and financial empowerment unhindered by the American government</p>

<p>At nearly 400,000 people, the Navajo Nation is one of the largest Native American tribes in the United States. It’s also one of the most impoverished, with <a href="https://www.welfareinfo.org/poverty-rate/">poverty statistics</a> closer to the world’s least developed countries than its neighboring cities of Phoenix, Arizona, or Santa Fe, New Mexico.</p>

<p>Nearly 50% of Navajo are unemployed, 40% don’t have running water, 32% live without electricity, and over 30% live below the poverty line, according to an April 2021 <a href="https://docs.house.gov/meetings/II/II24/20210421/112468/HHRG-117-II24-Wstate-HaaseW-20210421-SD022.pdf">testimony</a> before Congress.</p>

<p>Generational poverty for Native American populations has been the focus of an abundance of government research and spending. Most solutions for the issues center on injecting federal dollars into local economies through subsidies, special business licenses and community work.</p>

<p>What these solutions don’t propose, however, is giving tools for lasting individual empowerment to these indigienous populations. Indeed, the Navajo Nation is one of the most visible representations of living in a split monetary system: One with access to American capital, but lack of formal control over capital deployment.</p>

<p>But a silent financial revolution is occurring on Navajo land, and it’s fueled by the growth of a new industry: Bitcoin mining. “A Navajo person can’t own the land…”</p>

<p>The broken Navajo economy is the product of numerous treaties signed between the United States government and tribes during America’s westward expansion. Most treaties abdicated direct control of tribal people to the tribe itself, including government functions, taxation rights and law enforcement. But two major responsibilities remained in U.S. hands: trusteeship of land and control of the currency.</p>

<p>These stipulations have had predictable financial consequences.</p>

<p>As the trustee, the federal government leases Indian land out for uses such as farming, logging or mining. The U.S. government also manages the money accrued from such activities on behalf of the nations. Decades of mismanagement culminated in 2012 with a <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2016/09/27/495627997/u-s-government-to-pay-492-million-to-17-american-indian-tribes">$492 million settlement</a> between 17 tribes and the Obama administration.</p>

<p>Yet, the leasing system itself continues to hamper progress against poverty.</p>

<p>“The federal government took the land rights away from the Navajo people,” Navajo Tribal Authority President Walter Hasse told Compass Mining in an interview. “So a Navajo person can’t own the land that their home is on. If you don’t own the land, then how do you borrow the money to build a house on the land?”</p>

<h2 id="the-buckskin-curtain">The Buckskin Curtain</h2>

<p>Tribal sovereignty does not extend to currency either. As U.S. citizens, Native Americans are taxed in dollars. And while it’s difficult to say the dollar has been a net negative for tribes, restrictions around how money can be used within the incumbent financial system could be considered one.</p>

<p>Called “<a href="https://www.minneapolisfed.org/article/2000/breaching-the-buckskin-curtain">the buckskin curtain</a>,” Indian tribes have not only been slow to adopt financial tools, but impeded from accessing them due to national sovereignty. Only <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/native-american-owned-banks-by-state-5085713">32 Native American financial institutions are in existence today</a>, constituting the smallest percentage of minority-owned deposit institutions compared. Among other concerns, tribes worry accepting a bank charter from the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC) would interfere with their national status.</p>

<p>For example, where would a banking dispute be heard in court? In reservation courtrooms or in Washington? And what evidence do Native American tribes have that due process would be followed?</p>

<p>These questions have pushed tribes outside of the U.S. financial system by either being unable or unwilling to operate within the commercial banking sector.</p>

<h2 id="uranium-and-coal">Uranium And Coal</h2>

<p>Employment and currency only show half of the picture of economic damage though.</p>

<p>During the 20th century, energy firms outside of Navajo land signed contracts with the Navajo Nation to source and extract its abundant energy resources, especially coal and uranium.</p>

<p>hat coal was used to power cities from Santa Fe, New Mexico, to Los Angeles, California – illuminating, watering and powering a once sparsely populated portion of the United States. Years later, the power plants are coming down, leaving the Navajo little to show for leasing their land to outsiders, <a href="https://www.nrdc.org/stories/after-local-coal-mine-shuts-down-these-navajo-and-hopi-communities-seek-just-transition">minus</a> poisoned groundwater and abandoned coal pits.</p>

<p>Over 4 million tons of uranium were also mined on Navajo land from 1950 onward. While it fed Uncle Sam’s Cold War appetite, Navajo uranium would have devastatingly-long terminal effects on the indiginous people and their land. Some 27% of Navajo have heightened levels of uranium in their bodies, according to a 2016 <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2016/04/10/473547227/for-the-navajo-nation-uranium-minings-deadly-legacy-lingers">study</a>, while over 500 open-air uranium mines remain in various stages of cleanup.
Before Bitcoin, “mining” has carried very negative connotations for most of the Navajo Nation.</p>

<h2 id="bitcoin-mining">Bitcoin Mining</h2>

<p>In 2017, a small Canadian firm named West Block approached the Navajo about tapping Navajo energy for a Bitcoin mine on Navajo land.</p>

<p>Currently using 8 megawatts (MW), the new mine is already in the process of doubling its size. That’s equivalent to about 3,000 machines of various types powering and protecting the Bitcoin network using Navajo energy.</p>

<p>But it’s not just about the machines. It’s about the output of those machines in the context of a people group who’ve gone without many of the benefits the nominal American enjoys.</p>

<p>For example, the facility currently employs two full-time employees. With the expansion, that number will grow to eleven. The money created from the mine will then circulate into the local economy. It may seem insignificant now, but mining bitcoin on Navajo land is a very real source of future Navajo wealth, employment, and economic recovery.</p>

<p>The Navajo mines also represent the Navajo Nation creating wealth for themselves with their energy. Bitcoin mining brings demand for energy to wherever the energy source is. Navajo energy now has a non-stop and quickly-growing demand brought to their land with the profits paid to the Navajo Nation.</p>

<p>Lastly, the Navajo Bitcoin mines represent financial inclusion. Bitcoin mining is the first small step for broad bitcoin adoption by the Navajo Nation. Opting into a free and open-internet money protocol with a physical presence among the Navajo has unlimited potential for economic growth and wealth creation.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why The Navajo Are Mining Bitcoin William Foxley - Bitcoin Magazine]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mining Industry</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/18/mining-industry.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mining Industry" /><published>2022-04-18T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2022-04-18T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/18/mining-industry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/18/mining-industry.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="some-of-the-requirements-might-be-challenging-for-smaller-publicly-traded-miners-to-comply-with-however">Some of the requirements might be challenging for smaller publicly-traded miners to comply with, however.</h4>
<p><a href="https://www.coindesk.com/author/aoyon-ashraf/"><strong>By Aoyon Ashraf</strong></a></p>

<p><img src="../../../../assets/images/posts/img3.jpeg" alt="'image'" />
<em>Marathon Digital CEO Fred Thiel at the Bitcoin 2021 conference in Miami, Florida</em></p>

<p><a href="https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-46">This week’s proposal</a> by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) for publicly traded companies to report information on greenhouse-gas emissions and risks related to climate change seem like they could be major challenges for energy-intensive crypto mining firms. However, several in the industry say they’re not that concerned about the potential new rules and even welcome them.</p>

<p>The SEC’s proposal would require publicly traded companies to report greenhouse-gas emissions from their operations and from the energy they consume, and some to obtain independent certification of their estimates. Among crypto-linked companies, digital asset miners would be the most affected by such rules, given their demand for large amounts of energy to run their operations.</p>

<p><em><strong>Read more</strong>: <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/layer2/miningweek/2022/03/21/crypto-mining-the-energy-crisis-and-the-end-of-esg/">Crypto Mining, the Energy Crisis and the End of ESG*</a></em></p>

<p><a href="https://pub.ey.com/public/2021/2112/2112-3933703/blockchain-summit-2022/index.html"><img src="../../../../assets/images/posts/img4.jpeg" alt="'image'" /></a></p>

<p>“We welcome it,” said Fred Thiel, CEO of Marathon Digital (MARA), one of the largest publicly traded bitcoin mining companies, which aims to make its operations <a href="https://ir.marathondh.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1278/marathon-digital-holdings-announces-bitcoin-production-and">100% carbon neutral</a> by the end of 2022. “We don’t think as a miner, complying with the reporting requirements is going to be necessarily onerous,” he said, adding that the report would add transparency for Marathon’s “shareholders and to the community that we serve.”</p>

<p>The bill will also highlight the miners that use more renewable energy and help investors decide which companies will fit their environmental, social and governance (ESG) mandate, noted Ethan Vera, co-founder and chief operating officer of crypto mining and data firm Luxor Technologies.</p>

<p>“The latest proposed bill by the SEC for public companies to disclose the amount of emissions that they produce will shed light on the miners that aren’t using renewable energy,” Vera told CoinDesk. “A growing [number] of public investors have strict ESG guidelines that guide their investment decisions and make them prioritize bitcoin miners that fit in that category,” he added.</p>

<p>With the U.S. becoming the digital asset mining capital of the world, after <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/learn/china-crypto-bans-a-complete-history/">China’s sweeping ban</a> on the crypto sector, the impact of crypto mining on the environment has become a big debate both in the U.S. and around the world. Most recently, the Environmental Conservation Committee of the New York State Assembly voted on Tuesday afternoon to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-03-22/bitcoin-mining-ban-bill-advances-in-new-york-state-assembly?sref=3REHEaVI">move along a proposed law</a> that would ban so-called proof-of-work <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/learn/2020/12/16/what-is-proof-of-work/">(PoW)</a> cryptocurrency mining for two years. Earlier this month, a similar PoW ban <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2022/03/14/proposal-limiting-proof-of-work-is-rejected-in-eu-parliament-committee-vote-sources/">narrowly failed to pass</a> in a European Union Parliament committee vote.</p>

<p>These efforts to regulate the mining industry may not have come into effect yet, but it shows that lawmakers around the world and U.S. are taking a hard look at the environmental impact of crypto mining. “The SEC’s agenda isn’t startling, given Gary Gensler’s past statements and the Biden administration’s goal to tackle perceived climate risks,” said Will Foxley, content director at bitcoin mining service provider Compass Mining, as well as co-host of CoinDesk TV’s <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/tv/the-hash/">“The Hash.”</a></p>

<p><em><strong>Read More</strong>: <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/layer2/miningweek/2022/03/21/what-does-a-crypto-mining-farm-look-like-striking-photos-from-siberia-to-spain/">What Does a Crypto Mining Farm Look Like? Striking Photos From Siberia to Spain</a></em></p>

<h3 id="an-advantage-for-larger-firms">An advantage for larger firms</h3>

<p>The SEC’s proposal will be open for public comment for at least two months before the agency will begin its work on a final rule. However, if the proposal requires companies to report more detailed emission disclosures, it may be challenging to comply with, said Zach Bradford, CEO of CleanSpark (CLSK), a Nasdaq-listed bitcoin miner that uses renewable energy sources.</p>

<p>Overall, the bill would require firms to disclose their governance of climate-related risk; the material impact, if any, of those risks on a firm’s business, strategy or outlook; and how these risks might affect its financial statements. Bradford thinks this part will be easily handled by miners.</p>

<p>However, the proposed bill would also require companies to disclose varying levels of information about their own emissions. Scope 1 pertains to direct greenhouse (GHG) emissions that occur from sources that are controlled or owned by an organization – for example emissions associated with fuel combustion in boilers, furnaces and vehicles, according to <a href="https://www.epa.gov/climateleadership/scope-1-and-scope-2-inventory-guidance#:~:text=Scope%202%20emissions%20are%20indirect,of%20the%20organization's%20energy%20use.">the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)</a>. Scope 2 emissions are indirect GHG emissions associated with the purchase of electricity, steam, heat or cooling. Finally, the bill would also require some companies to report Scope 3 details, which include the emission disclosures of its supply chain and customers.</p>

<p>This level of detail might take a long time for miners and other companies to comply with. “I would expect that reporting of level 1 and level 2 emissions in a mandatory fashion will encounter an uphill battle,” Bradford said, adding that complying with them will be “fairly heavy and expensive lift, especially for smaller filers.”</p>

<p>Compass’s Foxley agreed. “The difficulty for miners comes in terms of reporting. More regulation means more paperwork, which increases overhead,” he said. “We’ve seen this story before in other industries: large-capital backed miners will benefit at the expense of smaller players.”</p>

<p>Large companies may not be completely spared either, however, if they are required to include independent assurance of their Scope 3 emission disclosures, Bradford said, noting that “if this portion does pass, I would expect a fairly long adoption period being added to a final rule.”</p>

<p>Either way, Bradford said he expects CleanSpark will not be impacted significantly by the proposed new rules. “At CleanSpark, we are always aiming to be ahead of the regulatory environment so we anticipate a minimal impact to our reporting and operational efforts should any of these rules be adopted,” Bradford said.</p>

<h3 id="incentives-to-use-cleaner-energy">Incentives to use cleaner energy</h3>
<p>Moreover, implementation of this new regulation by the miners will likely incentivize more adoption of renewable energy. “If this ends up raising the cost of capital for carbon-heavy miners, in the absence of any subsidies put in place to counter the effect at local or state levels, it will merely incentivize a shift in hash power away from the most carbon intensive parts of the U.S. and into the more renewables dominated regions,” said Chris Bendiksen, bitcoin research lead for digital asset manager CoinShares.</p>

<p>In fact, a fourth-quarter survey by the Bitcoin Mining Council estimated that bitcoin <a href="https://bitcoinminingcouncil.com/q4-bitcoin-mining-council-survey-confirms-sustainable-power-mix-and-technological-efficiency/">miners globally are now utilizing</a> a 58.5% mix of sustainable energy for their mining operations, up one percentage point from the third quarter.</p>

<p>The SEC’s proposed new regulation could raise the adoption of more sustainable energy sources for crypto miners even further. “By asking public companies to report their carbon footprint, I think, it only pushes people towards more use of renewable energy, which only helps the deployment of renewable energy and speeds our transition from legacy fuel types to renewables,” Marathon’s Thiel said.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some of the requirements might be challenging for smaller publicly-traded miners to comply with, however. By Aoyon Ashraf]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Revisiting Bitcoin’s Energy</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/17/revisiting-bitcoin-s-energy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revisiting Bitcoin’s Energy" /><published>2022-04-17T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2022-04-17T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/17/revisiting-bitcoin%E2%80%99s-energy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/17/revisiting-bitcoin-s-energy.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="revisiting-bitcoins-energy-problem-in-the-face-of-esg-investment-mandates">Revisiting Bitcoin’s Energy ‘Problem’ in the Face of ESG Investment Mandates</h1>

<h4 id="critics-of-bitcoins-energy-use-should-consider-its-relative-carbon-density-rather-than-the-absolute-amount-of-energy-used">Critics of Bitcoin’s energy use should consider its relative carbon density rather than the absolute amount of energy used.</h4>
<p><img src="../../../../assets/images/posts/img5.jpeg" alt="'image'" /></p>

<p>I get <a href="https://twitter.com/CoinDesk/status/1498402102426673158">really animated</a> when discussing Bitcoin’s energy use. And by “Bitcoin’s energy use,” I mean the amount of energy bitcoin mining uses. I tend to say Bitcoin’s energy use isn’t a problem and that we should instead focus on Bitcoin’s emissions. [Note: we capitalize the blockchain (Bitcoin) and use lowercase or trading symbols (bitcoin/BTC) for the asset.]</p>

<p>Before diving into any details, it’s important to make clear what bitcoin (BTC) mining is and why it needs to use a lot of energy. Mining is the mechanism that sustains the financial infrastructure of the Bitcoin network and it is energy intensive by design to provide ironclad security.</p>

<h2 id="the-comparison-game">The comparison game</h2>
<p>In a casual setting, my favorite way to showcase that Bitcoin’s energy use “doesn’t matter” is to append Bitcoin’s energy use to the U.S.’s energy consumption and ask if it looks like Bitcoin is using too much energy (see below).</p>

<p><img src="../../../../assets/images/posts/img7.png" alt="'image'" /></p>

<p>Using this graphic, it looks like the U.S. has an energy problem and, given China consumes 79% more energy than the U.S., China has an even bigger energy problem. Bitcoin only uses an estimated <a href="https://ccaf.io/cbeci/index">134 TWh of energy</a> per year, a scant 1.9% and 3.5% that China and the U.S. consume annually. You can imagine the path the rest of the conversation takes.</p>

<p>I included this graphic to illustrate that the comparison game is usually a waste of time. Bitcoiners often do this unproductively, comparing bitcoin mining energy consumption to Christmas light energy consumption or the like, and leaving the argument at that (Christmas lights do <a href="https://luxortechteam.medium.com/bitcoin-mining-uses-less-energy-than-christmas-lights-a-breakdown-of-bitcoin-mining-councils-q3-aacb2a5d4785">use a lot of energy</a>, however). I even did it in a report I published last April <a href="https://static.coindesk.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Does-Bitcoin-Have-an-Energy-Problem-CoinDesk-Research-2021.04.pdf">comparing it to video games</a>.</p>

<p>I probably committed a cardinal sin in that report by trying to convince the reader that Bitcoin’s energy use was “worth it” because Bitcoin is a “global, trustless, permissionless payment settlement network and a digital, <a href="https://www.fidelitydigitalassets.com/bin-public/060_www_fidelity_com/documents/FDAS/bitinvthessisstoreofvalue.pdf">aspirational store of value</a>.” Let’s save the morality lecture for another time and instead assume, for sake of argument, that Bitcoin is worth using energy.</p>

<h2 id="why-does-bitcoin-mining-need-to-use-energy">Why does bitcoin mining need to use energy?</h2>

<p>The shortest answer is that Satoshi Nakamoto, Bitcoin’s creator, thought the best way to fairly distribute bitcoins was by creating a system in which miners exchange something valuable – energy – for the right to claim the bitcoins (the shortest shortest answer is actually “<a href="https://twitter.com/davidzmorris/status/1503812775742689288">anti-spam</a>.</p>

<p>A longer answer should add something about the need to ward off attackers if you want to successfully <a href="https://uncommoncore.co/research-paper-a-model-for-bitcoins-security-and-the-declining-block-subsidy/">decentralize trust in a network</a>. Mining is energy-intensive so that it is prohibitively expensive to attack Bitcoin. Remember: Mining doesn’t use energy to validate transactions; energy consumption is the price exacted for securing the entire network.</p>

<p><img src="../../../../assets/images/posts/img6.png" alt="'image'" /></p>

<p>The preceding point about transaction validation is important because it is enticing to compare the energy density of Bitcoin transactions to something like Visa (V). Bitcoin can only handle seven transactions per second compared to Visa’s 24,000+. But, remember, Bitcoin doesn’t use energy to validate transactions. The miners’ job is to secure the network, add new blocks of data to the chain and win bitcoin in return. That’s what they spend energy on. They’re not primarily interested in validating transactions. That consensus on the true state of the network is primarily the job of non-mining, Bitcoin full nodes. Plus, Bitcoin transactions are not the same as Visa or other payment processors’ transactions. Bitcoin transactions <a href="https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Confirmation">provide (probabilistic) finality</a>, Visa’s don’t. Visa’s success depends on the success of separate systems. Visa’s “token” is not native to its network.</p>

<p><img src="../../../../assets/images/posts/img8.png" alt="'image'" /></p>

<h2 id="lets-talk-about-bitcoins-emissions-instead">Let’s talk about Bitcoin’s emissions instead</h2>

<p>A growing number of institutions have recognized the importance of environmental, social and governance (ESG) investing and have implemented internal mandates. Ignoring the “SG” for a moment (although they are immensely <a href="https://bitcoinmagazine.com/culture/check-your-financial-privilege">important and relevant to Bitcoin</a>,) it makes sense from an investment perspective to consider the environmental impact of Bitcoin’s energy use.</p>

<p>Bitcoin’s environmental impact has more to do with the greenhouse gas emissions (mainly carbon) associated with the production of the energy used for mining and less to do with the absolute amount of energy it consumes. We’ll consider renewable energy sources like solar, hydro and wind power as “clean” given their relatively low carbon density (ignoring their <a href="https://www.fisheries.noaa.gov/national/habitat-conservation/improving-fish-migration-hydropower-dams">negative externalities</a> for now). The cleaner the energy mix, the smaller the environmental impact.</p>

<p>A common environmental critique against bitcoin mining was that most miners were in China (&gt;80% in February 2020), a country highly dependent on coal-fired energy (although Chinese miners used a <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2020/04/28/chinese-city-known-for-bitcoin-mining-seeks-blockchain-firms-to-burn-excess-hydropower/">surprising amount of clean energy</a>). When China banned <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2021/05/21/bitcoin-falls-as-china-calls-for-crackdown-on-crypto-mining-trading/">crypto mining in May 2021</a>, miners left for the U.S., Kazakhstan and Russia. Time will tell whether those miners will settle on using clean energy sources, but they seem largely set on doing so, at least in the U.S..</p>

<p>In the report <a href="https://static.coindesk.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Does-Bitcoin-Have-an-Energy-Problem-CoinDesk-Research-2021.04.pdf">I wrote last year</a>, I relied on <a href="https://www.jbs.cam.ac.uk/faculty-research/centres/alternative-finance/publications/3rd-global-cryptoasset-benchmarking-study/">research published by Cambridge University</a> to support the position that bitcoin mining uses a respectable percentage of renewables in its energy mix. The 2020 study suggested that 39% of total energy for Bitcoin mining came from renewable sources in 2019 (<a href="https://www.jbs.cam.ac.uk/faculty-research/centres/alternative-finance/publications/2nd-global-cryptoasset-benchmark-study/#.YjDlmXrMKUl">compared to 28%</a> in 2018) with 76% of miners using renewable sources as part of their energy mix.</p>

<p>Since then, the <a href="https://bitcoinminingcouncil.com/">Bitcoin Mining Council</a> (BMC), a forum of Bitcoin miners aimed at promoting energy usage transparency, sharing best practices and educating the broader public on the benefits of Bitcoin and bitcoin mining, has shared data that suggests 58.5% of global bitcoin mining <a href="https://bitcoinminingcouncil.com/q4-bitcoin-mining-council-survey-confirms-sustainable-power-mix-and-technological-efficiency/">uses renewable energy</a> (66.1% for BMC members). That’s relatively clean. It is worth noting that inclusion in the BMC is entirely optional, so there might be some <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social-desirability_bias">social-desirability response bias</a> to sort through in their survey data.</p>

<p>I get really animated when discussing Bitcoin’s energy use. And by “Bitcoin’s energy use,” I mean the amount of energy bitcoin mining uses. I tend to say Bitcoin’s energy use isn’t a problem and that we should instead focus on Bitcoin’s emissions. [Note: we capitalize the blockchain (Bitcoin) and use lowercase or trading symbols (bitcoin/BTC) for the asset.]
Before diving into any details, it’s important to make clear what bitcoin (BTC) mining is and why it needs to use a lot of energy. Mining is the mechanism that sustains the financial infrastructure of the Bitcoin network and it is energy intensive by design to provide ironclad security.
You’re reading Crypto Long &amp; Short, our weekly newsletter featuring insights, news and analysis for the professional investor. Sign up here to get it in your inbox every Sunday.</p>

<p>The comparison game
In a casual setting, my favorite way to showcase that Bitcoin’s energy use “doesn’t matter” is to append Bitcoin’s energy use to the U.S.’s energy consumption and ask if it looks like Bitcoin is using too much energy (see below).
Bitcoin energy consumption vs U.S. (University of Cambridge Centre for Alternative Finance)
Read more: How Bitcoin Mining Works
Using this graphic, it looks like the U.S. has an energy problem and, given China consumes 79% more energy than the U.S., China has an even bigger energy problem. Bitcoin only uses an estimated 134 TWh of energy per year, a scant 1.9% and 3.5% that China and the U.S. consume annually. You can imagine the path the rest of the conversation takes.
I included this graphic to illustrate that the comparison game is usually a waste of time. Bitcoiners often do this unproductively, comparing bitcoin mining energy consumption to Christmas light energy consumption or the like, and leaving the argument at that (Christmas lights do use a lot of energy, however). I even did it in a report I published last April comparing it to video games.
Read more: Does Bitcoin Have an Energy Problem?</p>

<p>I probably committed a cardinal sin in that report by trying to convince the reader that Bitcoin’s energy use was “worth it” because Bitcoin is a “global, trustless, permissionless payment settlement network and a digital, aspirational store of value.” Let’s save the morality lecture for another time and instead assume, for sake of argument, that Bitcoin is worth using energy.
Why does bitcoin mining need to use energy?
The shortest answer is that Satoshi Nakamoto, Bitcoin’s creator, thought the best way to fairly distribute bitcoins was by creating a system in which miners exchange something valuable – energy – for the right to claim the bitcoins (the shortest shortest answer is actually “anti-spam”).
A longer answer should add something about the need to ward off attackers if you want to successfully decentralize trust in a network. Mining is energy-intensive so that it is prohibitively expensive to attack Bitcoin. Remember: Mining doesn’t use energy to validate transactions; energy consumption is the price exacted for securing the entire network.
Bitcoin network energy consumption
The preceding point about transaction validation is important because it is enticing to compare the energy density of Bitcoin transactions to something like Visa (V). Bitcoin can only handle seven transactions per second compared to Visa’s 24,000+. But, remember, Bitcoin doesn’t use energy to validate transactions. The miners’ job is to secure the network, add new blocks of data to the chain and win bitcoin in return. That’s what they spend energy on. They’re not primarily interested in validating transactions. That consensus on the true state of the network is primarily the job of non-mining, Bitcoin full nodes. Plus, Bitcoin transactions are not the same as Visa or other payment processors’ transactions. Bitcoin transactions provide (probabilistic) finality, Visa’s don’t. Visa’s success depends on the success of separate systems. Visa’s “token” is not native to its network.</p>

<p>Credit card transaction settlement vs. Bitcoin transaction settlement
Let’s talk about Bitcoin’s emissions instead
A growing number of institutions have recognized the importance of environmental, social and governance (ESG) investing and have implemented internal mandates. Ignoring the “SG” for a moment (although they are immensely important and relevant to Bitcoin), it makes sense from an investment perspective to consider the environmental impact of Bitcoin’s energy use.
Bitcoin’s environmental impact has more to do with the greenhouse gas emissions (mainly carbon) associated with the production of the energy used for mining and less to do with the absolute amount of energy it consumes. We’ll consider renewable energy sources like solar, hydro and wind power as “clean” given their relatively low carbon density (ignoring their negative externalities for now). The cleaner the energy mix, the smaller the environmental impact.
A common environmental critique against bitcoin mining was that most miners were in China (&gt;80% in February 2020), a country highly dependent on coal-fired energy (although Chinese miners used a surprising amount of clean energy). When China banned crypto mining in May 2021, miners left for the U.S., Kazakhstan and Russia. Time will tell whether those miners will settle on using clean energy sources, but they seem largely set on doing so, at least in the U.S..</p>

<p>In the report I wrote last year, I relied on research published by Cambridge University to support the position that bitcoin mining uses a respectable percentage of renewables in its energy mix. The 2020 study suggested that 39% of total energy for Bitcoin mining came from renewable sources in 2019 (compared to 28% in 2018) with 76% of miners using renewable sources as part of their energy mix.
Since then, the Bitcoin Mining Council (BMC), a forum of Bitcoin miners aimed at promoting energy usage transparency, sharing best practices and educating the broader public on the benefits of Bitcoin and bitcoin mining, has shared data that suggests 58.5% of global bitcoin mining uses renewable energy (66.1% for BMC members). That’s relatively clean. It is worth noting that inclusion in the BMC is entirely optional, so there might be some social-desirability response bias to sort through in their survey data.</p>

<h2 id="where-do-we-go-from-here">Where do we go from here?</h2>

<p>There were plenty of other ESG related topics I could have covered in this like how bitcoin mining could incentivize <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2021/07/14/bitcoin-is-already-incentivizing-renewable-energy/">more renewable energy</a> generation, improve <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/business/2022/02/03/texas-crypto-miners-shuttering-operations-as-winter-storm-approaches/">electrical grid intermittency</a>, revitalize <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/02/24/1081252187/bitcoin-cryptocurrency-china-us">local economies</a>, empower <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2021/11/10/why-shouldnt-the-navajo-mine-bitcoin/">oft-forgotten communities</a>, or act as a “<a href="https://www.seetee.io/static/shareholder_letter-6ae7e85717c28831bf1c0eca1d632722.pdf">load balancing economic battery</a>.” In reality bitcoin mining and its energy use is a complicated, multidisciplinary topic. By way of example, my view is that an investment in Bitcoin could be considered an investment in ESG, given its potential impact on energy generation. This column on its own doesn’t represent a full defense of that thesis because there are so many angles that weren’t considered.</p>

<p>At the very least, I hope this inspires more discussions about Bitcoin’s true energy cleanliness and broader impact.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Revisiting Bitcoin’s Energy ‘Problem’ in the Face of ESG Investment Mandates]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Icc</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/16/icc.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Icc" /><published>2022-04-16T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2022-04-16T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/16/icc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/16/icc.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="ipcc-cites-cryptocurrency-as-carbon-emissions-factor-in-latest-climate-report">IPCC cites cryptocurrency as carbon emissions factor in latest climate report</h1>

<p>A new report from the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) released Monday <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2022/apr/04/ipcc-report-now-or-never-if-world-stave-off-climate-disaster">contained dire warnings</a> about future climate risks.</p>

<p><a href="https://report.ipcc.ch/ar6wg3/pdf/IPCC_AR6_WGIII_FinalDraft_FullReport.pdf">The report from the IPCC</a>, an intergovernmental panel within the United Nations, was the third in a series of reports examining the state of climate change mitigation efforts. The panel said in a statement Mondy that “[w]ithout immediate and deep emissions reductions across all sectors, limiting global warming to 1.5°C is beyond reach.”</p>

<p>Included in the more than 2,000-page report were a pair of mentions of cryptocurrency networks as a carbon emissions risk.</p>

<p>As per the report, “large improvements in information storage, processing and communications technologies, including artificial intelligence, will affect emissions. They can enhance energy-efficient control, reduce transaction cost for energy production and distribution, improve demand-side management…and reduce the need for physical transport.”</p>

<p><em>“However, data centres and related IT systems (including blockchain) are electricity-intensive and will raise demand for energy – cryptocurrencies may be a global source of C02 if the electricity production is not decarbonized – and there is also a concern that information technologies can compound and exacerbate current inequalities.”</em></p>

<p>But governments play a key role in determining whether technology reduces or increases emissions, the authors note. “Overall, the challenge will be to enhance the synergies and minimize the trade-offs and rebounds, including taking account of ethical and distributional dimensions.”</p>

<p>Later, the report states that “digitalization, automation and artificial intelligence, as general-purpose technologies, may lead to a plethora of new products and applications that are likely to be efficient on their own but may also lead to undesirable changes or absolute increases in demand for products.” This section later goes on to state:</p>

<p><em>“The energy requirements for cryptocurrencies is also a growing concern, although considerable uncertainty exists surrounding the energy use of their underlying blockchain infrastructure.”</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[IPCC cites cryptocurrency as carbon emissions factor in latest climate report]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Women In Crypto</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/15/women-in-crypto.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Women In Crypto" /><published>2022-04-15T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2022-04-15T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/15/women-in-crypto</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/15/women-in-crypto.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="women-in-crypto-will-solve-more-than-just-a-diversity-problem">Women in crypto will solve more than just a diversity problem</h1>
<h6 id="hiring-women-into-leadership-positions-will-do-more-than-just-diversify-this-arm-of-the-finance-industry-theyll-impact-sustainability-and-esg-issues-for-the-better">Hiring women into leadership positions will do more than just diversify this arm of the finance industry; they’ll impact sustainability and ESG issues for the better.</h6>
<p><img src="../../../../assets/images/posts/img2.jpg" alt="'image'" /></p>

<p>Wall Street has long been dominated by men. Though the percentage of men and women entering the field is roughly equal, finance is still largely a male-dominated industry with men typically rising to the top faster than women. As digital currencies take root, crypto companies have an opportunity to be far more inclusive—but they better start now.</p>

<p>The data doesn’t lie: Crypto companies are already experiencing a diversity problem. According to <a href="https://www.thestreet.com/investing/cryptocurrency/less-than-5-of-crypto-entrepreneurs-are-women">The Street,</a> less than 5% of crypto founders are women. And the same goes for those investing in digital currencies. Bitcoin was initially built around encouraging financial equity, but 75% of crypto holders are men, as mentioned in a <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=122276X1583643&amp;isjs=1&amp;jv=15.2.4-stackpath&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fastcompany.com%2F90740927%2Fwomen-in-crypto-will-solve-more-than-just-a-diversity-problem&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gemini.com%2Fstate-of-us-crypto&amp;xs=1&amp;xtz=-240&amp;xuuid=0d122cd21393a1f84c0d5150cfaf3930&amp;xjsf=other_click__contextmenu%20%5B2%5D">2021 State of U.S. Crypto report.</a> Even more interesting is that crypto has seemingly broken down race barriers where other industries have not. <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/30/cryptocurrency-has-a-big-gender-problem.html">Data from CNBC</a> reported that people of all races are about equally likely to own cryptocurrency. Yet cryptocurrency hasn’t managed to break down gender disparities, with men twice as likely to invest in crypto as women.</p>

<h4 id="diversifying-the-voices-in-crypto">DIVERSIFYING THE VOICES IN CRYPTO</h4>
<p>There’s no doubt that as an industry, crypto could benefit from more women in leadership positions. Research reported in the Harvard Business Review <a href="https://hbr.org/2019/06/research-women-score-higher-than-men-in-most-leadership-skills">places</a> women ahead of men in resilience, self-development, and initiative-taking. It would be wise to hire more women into leadership positions in crypto not only for diversity of thought but also to help attract a wider pool of investors.</p>

<p>If we don’t diversify the voices in the crypto conversation, we’ll see a repeat of the inequality that exists in traditional finance. That starts with education efforts directed at women. Companies must get women talking about crypto as part of their financial future. And what better way to get women talking than seeing a woman leading the path in an executive role?</p>

<h4 id="women-will-lead-the-way-to-a-more-esg-focused-industry">WOMEN WILL LEAD THE WAY TO A MORE ESG-FOCUSED INDUSTRY</h4>
<p>Environmental, social, and governance (ESG) investing is on the rise—especially among women. Investors are more aware than ever of these non-financial factors, and they take them into consideration when identifying the risk and opportunities of investments. A recent study by <a href="https://www.rbcwealthmanagement.com/en-us/newsroom/2021-04-06/women-are-leading-the-charge-for-environmental-social-and-governance-esg-investing-in-the-us-amid-growing-demand-for-responsible-investing-solutions">RBC Wealth Management</a> found that women are more than twice as likely as men to say it’s extremely important that the companies they invest in incorporate ESG factors into their policies and procedures.</p>

<p>It’s no secret that cryptocurrency comes with a significant environmental impact. As noted by <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/cryptocurrency-and-the-esg-issue%3A-why-cryptos-are-more-esg-friendly-than-you-think">Nasdaq,</a> the processing power required to mine the cryptocurrency and complete transactions in it is huge: a single Bitcoin block may consume more than 2,000 kilowatt-hours of electricity to be mined, which equals the amount of power consumed by the average American household over 72.2 days.</p>

<p>As sustainable investing continues to grow, women will take the lead as investors, crypto decision-makers, and executives, lending an ESG lens to strategies for pushing the industry forward, rethinking solutions to environmental concerns, and setting businesses up for future sustainability initiatives.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Women in crypto will solve more than just a diversity problem Hiring women into leadership positions will do more than just diversify this arm of the finance industry; they’ll impact sustainability and ESG issues for the better.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Clean Energy</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/14/clean-energy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clean Energy" /><published>2022-04-14T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2022-04-14T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/14/clean-energy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:3000/article/2022/04/14/clean-energy.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="how-clean-energy-can-further-the-mass-adoption-of-crypto">How Clean Energy Can Further the Mass Adoption of Crypto</h1>
<h3 id="soluna-computing-helps-make-renewable-affordable-energy-the-worlds-primary-power-source-by-building-green-crypto-mining-facilities-and-data-centers-where-energy-would-otherwise-be-left-to-waste">Soluna computing helps make renewable, affordable energy the world’s primary power source by building green crypto mining facilities and data centers where energy would otherwise be left to waste</h3>

<p><img src="../../../../assets/images/posts/img10.webp" alt="'image'" /></p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>The Bitcoin Mining Council is a “community of 36 mining companies, representing about half of the network…the whole focus of that council is to track energy consumption, its sources, and how much of it is green.”</strong></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>A large portion of the network utilizes renewable energy sources, and that number is set to rise once Soluna joins the Bitcoin Mining Council.</strong></p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Bitcoin and crypto still have yet to find a positive place in society. Much of the public either hasn’t heard of crypto or regards it as some kind of fringe asset class used by criminals and geeks. That’s not to mention the bad reputation that mining has earned with regard to its environmental impact.</p>

<p>But what if these problems could be tackled in tandem? Could associating a surge in renewable energy usage among miners help to bring crypto into the mainstream while cleaning up its image at the same time?</p>

<p>The team at Soluna believes that not only is the answer a resounding yes, but that this could be the ideal strategy for mass adoption of crypto.</p>

<h2 id="the-efficiency-of-mining">The Efficiency of Mining</h2>

<p>We spoke with John Belizaire, CEO of Soluna, to get his thoughts on the subject.</p>

<p>First, when asked the question “is Bitcoin an efficient use of energy?”, John replied:</p>

<p>“The answer is yes, it is, based on its use case. And the use case is protecting trillions of dollars of value, potentially for a new form of digital asset that holds the wealth of hundreds of millions of people around the world.”</p>

<p>He also mentioned that the Bitcoin network uses a sort of autonomous feedback loop that perpetuates its security. As it “senses the amount of computing power available to attack the network,” the mining difficulty then adjusts upward, making it “harder and harder for the [proof-of-work] problem to be solved,” creating an ever-stronger barrier of security. This process requires an increasing amount of energy, adding to the network’s security by making it more expensive for attackers to strike.</p>

<p>Rather than seeing this as a negative, transitioning to clean energy makes the increasing need for energy a positive attribute of the Bitcoin network.</p>

<h2 id="mining-energy-relative-to-other-energy-intensive-practices">Mining Energy Relative to Other Energy-Intensive Practices</h2>

<p>Perhaps the most compelling part of the conversation occurred when Belizaire cited a <a href="https://bitcoinminingcouncil.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/2021.07.01-BMC-Q2-2021-Materials.pdf">document</a> put out by the Bitcoin Mining Council.</p>

<p>First, he noted that in the early days of Bitcoin mining, the majority of hash rate may have been coming from fossil fuel-based sources. But over time, particularly over “the last two years, just about everything has shifted over to more of a green energy transition.”</p>

<p>He then explained that the Bitcoin Mining Council is a “community of 36 mining companies, representing about half of the network…the whole focus of that council is to track energy consumption, its sources, and how much of it is green.”</p>

<p>Looking at the slide deck provided by the Bitcoin Mining Council, it shows that 66%, or two-thirds of the entire network currently comes from renewable energy sources. “When we get added that will probably bump up because we’re very green,” he said, referring to Soluna’s plans to join the council in the near future.</p>

<p>The slide deck also showed that industries like gold mining, the military-industrial complex, construction and others each dwarf the totality of Bitcoin mining’s energy usage.</p>

<p>In terms of total energy used, Bitcoin mining only uses about 10% more energy per year than holiday lights. That’s right – Christmas lights use almost as much energy as Bitcoin does to secure nearly a trillion dollars’ worth of value, according to the Bitcoin Mining Council.</p>

<h2 id="renewable-energy-on-the-rise">Renewable Energy on the Rise</h2>

<p>Overall, the reality of Bitcoin’s energy usage depends on the frame of reference being used.</p>

<p>It may be true that a single transaction requires more energy than an entire household uses in 24 hours, for example. But it’s also true that in a given year, the entire network uses little more energy than holiday lights. Depending on how things are framed, anyone can argue that mining is either the most ridiculous waste of energy or the most efficient and green use of energy.</p>

<p>The fact of the matter, however, is that a large portion of the network utilizes renewable energy sources, and that number is set to rise once Soluna joins the Bitcoin Mining Council. This could help lead to mass adoption of Bitcoin by fostering a greater understanding of Bitcoin’s potential positive impact on electrical grids.</p>

<h2 id="making-things-mainstream">Making Things Mainstream</h2>

<p>Bitcoin miners are considered to be a “flexible load.” That means their energy usage can be turned on or off at a moment’s notice with ease. Doing so doesn’t disrupt the process of mining at all.</p>

<p>This makes miners quite desirable to grid operators, who have to deal with an increasingly unpredictable supply of energy due to increasing amounts of power coming from wind and solar, which can be unreliable at times. When power from renewables decreases, grid operators can simply ask miners to cease operations for a while, reducing strain on the grid.</p>

<p>At the same time, local grids sometimes find themselves overloaded with an abundance of power produced by renewables. This energy goes to waste when there’s no demand for it. Fortunately, Bitcoin miners can step in and make use of that energy.</p>

<p>In this manner, the Bitcoin network could become an integral part of the electric grid – a very green one, in fact. Pockets of stranded energy that would otherwise go to waste can be utilized by Bitcoin miners, who can also shut down operations when grids become strained.</p>

<p>This makes Bitcoin not just a store of value or medium of exchange, but also an energy conservation tool. Once this concept has been fully grasped by the public, they will embrace Bitcoin mining and its proliferation. That acceptance will fuel faster adoption of Bitcoin by creating a virtuous cycle of greater usage followed by broader understanding, which leads to yet more adoption, and so on.</p>

<p>In the end, Bitcoin’s total energy usage is a bit of a red herring. It overlooks where that energy comes from as well as how miners can play a vital role in stabilizing power grids. When factoring in the role of renewables, stranded energy usage, and grid flexibility, it becomes clear that Bitcoin can be a net benefit to the way the world uses energy. Once a greater understanding of this becomes widespread, so too will acceptance of Bitcoin, and that acceptance will fuel yet more adoption and further awareness.</p>

<p><strong><em>This content is sponsored by <a href="https://www.solunacomputing.com/">Soluna Computing</a>. To read more about <a href="https://www.solunacomputing.com/">Soluna</a>, explore articles like <a href="https://blockworks.co/crypto-miners-go-to-congress/">Industry Execs Make Case For Crypto Mining Before Congress</a>.</em></strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How Clean Energy Can Further the Mass Adoption of Crypto Soluna computing helps make renewable, affordable energy the world’s primary power source by building green crypto mining facilities and data centers where energy would otherwise be left to waste]]></summary></entry></feed>